IL Cafe we have you
covered good to have you join us on IL
Cafe My Name Is Shel and today we're
going to be talking about something that
requires a lot of attention and focus
but perhaps in our country as I'm
realizing it doesn't get as much focus
and that is the area of Motor Vehicle
Insurance you know taken a back because
when you buy a car usually you know that
whole process of insurance is part of
the whole deal so I'm thinking who are
these people who somehow are managing
not to insure their vehicles and why
would they do that but questions will
get answered it's a stunning Revelation
really and it has of course led to a
shift in the approach to vehicle
insurance uh in India from the
authorities as well as insurance
companies so that's you know the silver
lining in that particular cloud in fact
ICI Lombard has been among the
innovators in this regard with a roster
of motor insurance products that address
pretty much all of these issues now on
this episode of a cafe I thought we
should you know arm ourselves with
wisdom and guidance and insight and
perspective so who better than nitin
Kanna business head motor business at
ICI Lombard to join us and talk about
the shifting ground no pun intended in
the motor vehicle insurance sector in
India today and how that really impacts
vehicle owners themselves and also the
automobile industry in general so that's
really the context I wanted to give you
before I welcome nian onto the show Nan
thank you so much for making us some
time welcome to the show and how are you
thanks I'm fine thanks for having me
here a pleasure and entirely and I have
to ask you since we're talking about
Motors right I'm reminded of the very
first set of wheels that I ever sat on
and that was a bicycle a BSA SLR that my
father bought for me as a as a gift when
I was in school what was yours I'm
curious to know did you what was a is
there a pet memory associated with the
first vehicle that you own I think you
said for most of us the first vehicle
would be cycle for which our parents
would have bought to us when we were
maybe in our early teens right but what
I remember would be my first scooter
which I bought after I got my job which
also my dad got for me that the first
automobile which I bought uh once I got
my job my MBA so that was the first
vleer yeah and while the first one
remains special actually in our context
of motor insurance every vehicle after
that remains as important or should
remain as important maybe if you could
tell us about some of the ground
realities of Motor Vehicle Insurance in
India a few things here I think one if
you to divide automobile into three
different segment there is a private car
there's a two there's a commercial
vehicles M reasonable level of uh
penetration insurance right two Che
challenges one I said since it's G more
in the internet of the country no such
uh kind of check by the authorities
second also the premium size for two whe
is so low that there's no interest from
the intermedi of the insurance company
to reach out to the customer right
another challenge which we get that no
IND industry we don't try hard enough to
renew a two wheeler than a private car
if you own a private car my sense you
will get at least five to six calls
before your renewal a two wheer customer
might not get that many
calls so that also impacts the overall
renewal rates and the unur market these
are some interesting points over here
with respect to the distinction the type
of vehicles that youve made over here
but then that brings me to a more even
more fundamental question that I think
all of our listeners would benefit from
why is the need for therefore motor
insurance at all why is it necessary for
a vehicle owner to purchase insurance
because you know from the look of it you
can make do without it also you can pay
for repairs you know sell it for
whatever price you might get buy another
vehicle uh so why buy insurance for my
car or bike or SUV or any other vehicle
if I can actually manage to take good
care of it that two parts of En my mind
one is that a classic debate in terms of
Self Insurance versus techn Insurance
outside whether it's for health or for
home we talking about motor but one of
the other product which I think I'll
highlight is that even for home lot of
us don't get insured because we think
that nothing happen going to happen to
my home it happen to neighbor home for
health insurance pation are still lower
in this country but if you look at how
the automobile industry is moving there
are two parts of automobile insurance
there is one which is the damage of the
vehicle and there is a third party if
you look at damage to the vehicle that
is largely what look at today the amount
of electronics or semiconductor which
goes into a car are far higher than it
goes into any other equipment right so
the cost of repair is also going up so
it makes lot of sense for people to
ensure their vehicle because of the even
the OD damage the other part of the
third party if you end up hitting
somebody on on a on a road a third party
damage which in India
unlimited mean that code can reward uh
any amount of reward to the person who
is affected the Nomine of the person who
is affected and you have to pay that
amount the premiums are as low as 5,000
6,000 rupes for an on damage in a
private car and be 700 r in a two wheer
so why would like to bear that liability
on you if you can get that through
insurance company by paying 700 rupees
yeah absolutely I think clearly there's
a huge Advantage for customer to renew
the vehicle I think there's more of
inertia lethar in the consumer not they
forget it than actually not doing it
yeah inertia lethargy and also probably
lack of awareness for example I'll tell
you my own story for a long time I
didn't understand the third party
Insurance aspect of it till my own
husband one day took my chav and hid it
in the box and say up you know I'm sorry
but you're not going to get drive this
car because third party insurance is not
there and that's when I
realized you know so um I think I'm
hoping a podcast like this or a show
like this will go a long way into
building that level of awareness into
people you know one more question that
really I think begs to be asked while we
are understanding the basics of the
space Nan is the uh industry size what
are some of the India specific
information the market uh size that you
can give us to help us understand why so
much of focus is being given to motor
insurance as an area for L reason it's a
mandatory product and when you buy a new
vehicle it is always insured that you
can't register vehle insurance so the
pention was very high at the time of the
new vehicle and then used to drive the
overall uh pre just premium for any
insurance company to invest in terms of
manpow in terms of the technology in
terms of the new product that is how it
is and if you look at Indian market in
terms of the automobile we have the
fastest growing market today in two
almost the largest market I don't think
any other country produces the two like
we do right which is mode of conven for
a regular indan today is a two wheer so
it's all a ripple effect in many ways
and suddenly when responding to that
question I realized that n must be the
go-to person for his family
members because you are such a subject
matter expert in even that areas of what
is available and what are the segments
and so on so that was fascinating to
hear more than actually advise on that
more for discounts what discount you can
get that is more which I get calls for
not for
advice the thing I want I think two
things today one is the waiting is very
high can you make it faster and plus the
discount yeah so we have an insight into
what kind of phone calls also nin is
Fielding most more often than not and
well we'll take a small little break and
on the other side we'll talk about some
of the interesting products that are
being Bor of this consumer need and itan
will tell us about both what are these
new expectations consumers have and what
are the products that icso lombar and
organizations like uh this actually have
catered to or tailored for these needs
stay with us on I Cafe it's nian Kanna
who's joining us
today IL Cafe we have you
covered back again on is Cafe we're
talking about a very important area and
that is Motor Vehicle Insurance Now nian
Products right we just spoke about the
realities the market realities some of
the trends Etc but it would be more
important for our listeners to
understand uh customer expectations and
products and how these two have aligned
to give us some of those great options
that you know ICS Lombard is so famous
for in with a you know plethora of very
interesting product so if you could tell
us a little bit about both those aspects
it would be great so I think said there
are there a basic insurance product
which third part liability which might
arise of the accident but uh we as
industry are very regulated till maybe a
year back I think post the new regime in
the regulator there lot of openness in
terms of filing of the product and the
products allowing the CH comp launch new
products right we also company launched
many products in last I a year or so
which is in helping the consumer to one
convenience and second also reducing
their premium in case they are driving
well right if you look at the industry
we used to earlier price based on Factor
like class of the vehicle or the
location so we used to assume Inda in
Delhi is a bad vehicle there could be
Inda which is d by maybe a businessman
Inda which is also driven by for example
I used to own Inda I used to drive maybe
10 km a day there another guy who a
businessman used to drive 100 km a day I
will Tre them same was how industry was
kind of pricing the uh the insurance for
quite some time I would say in last one
year a lot of that has changed we also
have products which link your civil
score to your insurance premiums I can
driving behavior to various modes I can
either put OB divice in your car which
will give me the data in terms of your
sudden breaking your sharp turns your
time of driving how much much you drive
and all that can help me to pricee you
better so I can price say ntin k
different from a sh because I know shal
drives much more safer than a n who is a
r similarly I can also say with somebody
who drives let's say 10 km a day or 300
km a month somebody who's driving let
say 300 3,000 km a month I can PR them
differently but the more you on road
more the of accident somebody who drives
less can be priced better somebody who
drives more in on the road two which
industry has which are links to
telematic they are very very common
abroad Western Country I think we also
on that Journey now with insurance
company started this pilot almost two
years back so we have sufficient data
now to price our customer based on their
driving behavior and how much they drive
the other point which I like to talk
about is more of a convenience platform
wherein in lot of our families there are
two or three like this Bombay might be a
lesser Trend but if you go to Delhi if
there are five adults in a family there
are five cars right or be four cars and
one bike based on the family uh graic
and you can ensure all the products in
one policy as you said you might forget
to renew your policy you have five car
you might forget to one policy right but
now I can we can ensure all your
vehicles in your family in one in one
bonus fantastic that gives you a lot of
convenience of not remembering all the
insurance dates and going for insurance
on one policy you can insure all the
vehicles the other product which we are
launched is basically based on the risk
of the customer which is Cil based score
M you must be aware that today all your
loans or credit cards get approved based
on your civil scores which tell your
cred worthiness right we do the analysis
of civil along with the loss beh of the
consumer weize that a good civil score
customer is also a better loss maybe it
drives better there lot hypo there but
there's clear correlation between a big
good civil score and a good driver you
launch product if your civil score is
more than 750 which is considered to be
good civil score we'll give you
additional discount on your premium so
that you can renew your vehicle with us
all the new products are coming in the
market now we have taken some lead in
terms of launching these products but my
sense of other players will also start
launching these product as the time
comes fantastic you know of all the
information that given us uh in terms of
the products available and some of the
benefits and how they're speaking or
addressing specific needs of the
customer so hyper personalized if I may
put it that way one thing that also
stood out which I really like from you
is even if it was an example you said
shal is a very good driver so I want to
take that part of the recording I want
to play to all my family members for
poster posterity so there's no doubt or
debate on the matter coming from nitin
Kanna himself and on that happy note
it's time to wrap up ale Cafe in it's
been a fun conversation understanding an
area that I think touches all of our
Lives all of us know at least somebody
who owns a vehicle even if we don't own
one ourselves so far and this kind of
information is critical in helping us
make those choices and decisions thank
you so much nin for joining us on I Cafe
today and helping us understand the
space thank you thank you for your time
it was a pleasure for my side thank you
you were listening to Il Cafe we have
you covered